Guide to the Margaret Strickland Papers 1880-1963 MSS.077
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Manuscripts
  - Subseries D: Short Fiction & Non-Fiction
    - "Aspidistra", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      10 Pages, Unbound
    - "Because of Stripey" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      “By Margaret Strickland, Author of ‘Michael Gerahty - Detective, ’ 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, London, [England] SW1, [Telephone Victoria 3287]”
      47 Pages, Unbound
    - "Bone Heads", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      7 Pages, Unbound
    - "Buying His Chance", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      17 Pages, Unbound
    - "By Stealth", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - “ ‘Carte Blanche’ or ‘Knight in Shining Armour’ ", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      “By Margaret Strickland, 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England] SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287”
      Measurements: 7.75” x 10”
    - "Cats -- and Gardens", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      1 Manuscript with Ephemera: “Horse Whispering” Article [Photocopy]
      “By Margaret Strickland, 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
      Typed & Printed
    - "Cheats", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      14 Pages, Unbound
    - "Cupid's Night Out", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      15 Pages, Unbound
    - "Dark Horses" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      43 Pages, Unbound
    - "Dido Speaking", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      28 Pages, Unbound
      Measurements: 7.75” x 10.5”
    - "Five Animal Short Stories", undated, circa 1920s (Box 4, Folder 20)
      1 Booklet of Ephemera with Notation: Newsprint Clippings of Strickland’s Stories in The Red Magazine & The Yellow Magazine
      “Bacchus on Duty”
      “Mrs. Woggins and the Parlour Snake” (Illustrated by F.W. Purvis)
      “Sanfarian”
      “Scorpio Tells the Tale”
      “Winkletop” (Illustrated by C. Amler)
      “By Margaret Strickland (Mrs. Richard Hugh Worley), 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
      50 Pages, Bound with Orange Cover
      Measurements: 7” x 8.75”
    - "Giving Jim His Chance: The True Story of Christine Lawson", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      “By Mrs. Margaret Worley (Strickland), 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
    - "Gommie's Jubilee Binge: A Cricket Story", undated, circa 1908 -1940 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      21 Pages, Unbound
    - "Gussie", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "Her Lucky Day" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      “By Margaret Strickland, ℅ Mrs. Mallet Veale [Diana Mary Strickland], Reydon, Gadzema, South Rhodesia, [Africa]; 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
      19 Pages, Unbound
      Measurements: 8” x 10.25”
    - "Her 'Unknown' ", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      25 Pages, Unbound
    - "It Is Not Only Elephants Who Remember", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      1 Manuscript Page with Notation
    - "More Than Coronets" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      “By Margaret Strickland, ℅ Mrs. Mallet Veale [Diana Mary Strickland], Reydon, Gadzema, South Rhodesia, [Africa]; 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England] SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
    - "Not the Same" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1950 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      Measurements: 8” x 11”
    - "Odd Fish", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      1 Manuscript Page
      1 Page, Unbound & Typed
      Measurements: 7.75” x 7.5”
    - "Of All the Queer Chances" Chapters I - X, undated, circa 1908 - 1950 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      1 Manuscript with Index, Notice & Notation
      169 Pages, Bound & Unbound
      Measurements: 8” x 10” - 11” x 4.5”
    - "Of All the Queer Chances" Chapters XI - XVIII, undated, circa 1908 - 1950 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      141 Pages, Bound & Unbound
    - "Our Friendly Garden Herbs", undated, circa 1908 - 1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      “By Margaret Strickland, F.R.H.S. [Fellow of the Royal Horticultural Society], 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
      9 Pages, Unbound
    - “Perchance To Dream”, undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      6 Pages, Unbound
    - "Posh Coat" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      “By Margaret Strickland, ℅ Mrs. Mallet Veale [Diana Mary Strickland], Reydon Farm, Gadzema, South Rhodesia, [Africa]; 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England, SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
      18 Pages, Unbound
    - "Queer Pets" with "Your Window Garden", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      2 Manuscripts
    - "Red Murder!", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "Romany Doctor", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - “ ‘Simples’ Not To Be Despised” with “Cures For Warts”, undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      “By Margaret Strickland (F.R.H.S. for 52 Years) [Fellow of the Royal Horticultural Society], 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England] SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287”
    - "The Advertisement" with "The Wonderful Advertisement", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      “By Margaret Strickland, 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England] SW1"
      20 Pages, Unbound
    - "The Blue Peristola", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      “By Margaret Strickland, F.R.H.S. [Fellow of the Royal Horticultural Society], 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
      16 Pages, Unbound
    - "The Bogey-Man", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      “By Margaret Strickland, 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
      13 Pages, Unbound
    - "The Calling Eyes", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      “By Margaret Strickland, 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1”
    - "The Carpet", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "The Case of Lottie Bursall", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      “By Margaret Strickland, Author of ‘Elusive Peg’ ‘Tales of Temptation,’ etc., 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1”
    - “The Chink In The Armour”, undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "The Curious Behavior of Seeds", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      “By Margaret Strickland, F.R.H.S. [Fellow of the Royal Horticultural Society], 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1”
    - "The Curse of Judith Thorne", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      “By Margaret Strickland, ℅ Curtis Brown, Limited, 6 Henrietta Street, Covent Garden, London, [England] WC2; 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1”
      Measurements: 7.5” x 10”
    - "The Feud" with "The Feud: A Dog Story (Self Told) By Don", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      “By Margaret Strickland, 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England SW1”
      34 Pages, Unbound
      Measurements: 8" x 10.5"
    - "The Flight", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "The Furniture", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "The Gate-Crasher", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "The Goad of Memory", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      “By Margaret Strickland, Author of ‘Tales of Temptation,’ ‘Elusive Peg,’ ‘Michael Gerahty,’ etc., 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1”
    - "The Good-Man Of This House", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      1 Manuscript with Editing & Musical Notation
    - "The Green Eyes of Beppe" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      41 Pages, Unbound
    - "The Hamper" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      “By Margaret Strickland, ℅ Mrs. Mallet Veale [Diana Mary Strickland], Reydon Farm, Gadzema, Southern Rhodesia, [Africa]; 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1”
      33 Pages, Unbound
    - "The Leopard Skin" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      32 Pages, Unbound
    - "[The] / A London Spice Box", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      1 Manuscript with Index & Notation: “Being A Selection Of The True Happenings At A London Residential Hotel, Told by Marita,” “Alternative Titles: Mixed Spice, Cap & Bells”
      “By Margaret Strickland (Mrs. Richard Hugh Worley), 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1”
      176 Pages, Bound & Unbound
      Measurements: 3” x 4.75” - 8” x 13”
    - “ ‘The Maroon Robe’ or ‘A Grave Affair' ", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "The Miniature", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      “By Margaret Strickland, ‘Tales of Temptation,’ ‘More Tales of Temptation,’‘Elusive Peg,’ ‘Michael Gerahty, Detective,’ ‘Fateful Numbers,’ etc., and Contributor To Many Magazines, Including ‘The Strand,’ 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287”
    - "The Modern Kid", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - "The Mummy Hand", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "The Ogre Next Door", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      26 Pages, Unbound
    - "The Porch of Wrong", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      1 Manuscript with Notation & Poetry by Habberton Lulham “If, in this City of Life, thy feet”
    - "The Question", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      “By Margaret Strickland, [88 Alderney Street, Victoria, London, England SW1, Telephone Victoria 3287]”
    - "The Ring", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - “The Story Of A Wasp”, undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      4 Pages, Unbound
    - "The Tarantula", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - "The Thug", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - "The Trap", 1924 October 8; undated, circa 1924 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      1 Manuscript with Correspondence, Notation & Synopsis
      Addressed To: “Miss Margaret Strickland, [88 Alderney Street, Victoria, London, England SW1]”
      Sent From: “L.J. Moreu, Pekalongan, [Central] Java, [Indonesia]”
      In Reference To: Business / Legal / Professional / Writing; Authorization to Publish Strickland’s Writing in Newspapers, According to Dutch Law
      Measurements: 8.5” x 11” - 8” x 13”
    - "The Wayfarer: A Real Experience", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - "The Woman Who Knew Too Much", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - "Traveling Companions" [2 Copies], undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      By Margaret Strickland, ℅ Mrs. Mallet Veale [Diana Mary Strickland], Reydon Farm, Gadzema, South Rhodesia, [Africa]; 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1”
    - "Twelve [Thirteen] Uncanny Stories", undated, circa 1922 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      1 Booklet of Ephemera with Notation: Newsprint Clippings of Strickland’s Stories in The Blue Magazine & The Red Magazine & The Violet Magazine “115 Fleet Street, London, [England] EC4”
      “Flowers In The Hedges”
      “Huldah Of ‘The Fastness’ ”
      “Ineligible”
      “Little Miss Ann”
      “The Fourth Dimension”
      “The Honeymoon Of Mr. Fiddle”
      “The Case Of Sir Alister Moeran”
      “The Keepers Of My Destiny”
      “The Mystery of Gable House”
      “The Nameless Terror”
      “The Phantom Third”
      “The Sword"
      “What The Foxgloves Knew”
      “By Margaret Strickland, 88 Alderney Street, Victoria, [London, England SW1]”
      114 Pages, Bound by String with Green Cover
      Printed & Handwritten in Ink & Pencil
      Measurements: 6.25” x 9.5”
    - "While Margot Slept", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "Wise Birds & Kind Birds", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      2 Pages, Unbound
    - "Woman's Inconsistency", undated, circa 1908 - 1940 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - [Unidentified Fragments], 1930 August - 1941 June; undated, circa 1885 - 1942 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Correspondence / Ephemera with Notation
      Addressed To: “Mr. Richard [Hugh] Worley, Esq., 88 Alderney Street, [Victoria, London, England] SW1”
      Sent From: “Deputy Divisional Controller of the Ministry of Labour, Divisional Office For Employment & Insurance, 59-62 Queen’s Gardens, London [England] WC2”; “Director W.H. Stringer of James Gibbons Limited, 15 Fisher Street, Southampton Row, London [England] WC1”; “John Barker & Company Limited, Stationery Department, High Street Kensington, London, [England] W8”; “London Manager of J&W Henderson Limited, Builders’ Merchants, Queen’s House, 28 Kingsway, London [England] WC2”; “Walker, Martineau & Company, 12 Manson Place, [London, England] SW7 via Furber & Maskell, Auctioneers, Surveyors, Valuers & Estate Agents, 3 Warwick Court, Gray’s Inn, London [England] WC1”
      In Reference To: Business / Financial / Professional; Advertisements, Employment, Stationery & Stamp Sales, Margaret's Tunbridge Wells High School [Kent, England] Notebook Cover; Lieutenant Colonel Bury, Harrolds’ Farm, Berden - de Beer & Son Repairs”
      37 Pages, Unbound
      Measurements: 8” x 12.5”
- Series III: "Illustrated Amateur Magazine"
  These materials are arranged chronologically. In the case that a record includes more than one date expression, the listing will begin with its earliest. If a record is physically undated, approximate ranges are provided. These records are noted "undated" and followed by a "circa" estimate determined by the range represented in the same series and or subseries.
  Series III: "Illustrated Amateur Magazine" features early examples Strickland sisters' art and writing. This series includes twelve issues of the title, a handmade publication Margaret created with her sisters Agnes, Diana Mary, and their friends in Bromley, Kent [now London], from 1897 - 1899. Despite their adolescent origins, these issues of "Illustrated Amateur Magazine" feature an especially acute knowledge of advertising and the magazine industry of the period. Contents include articles about current culture trends that range from art, bicycles, music, theater, to prize reader activities in the form of competitions and puzzles, to refined artwork in the form of ink drawings and watercolor paintings.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  These materials were treated by our conservation department for their fragile physical state, please handle with care.
  Animal Stories.; Advertisements.; Advertising, Classified -- Juvenile literature.; Newspapers.; Librettos (document genre for music).; Reviews (document genre); Young Adult Fiction, English; Help-wanted advertising -- Great Britain.; Poetry.; Piano music.; Correspondence.; Editorials.; Sheet music.; English poetry |y 19th century.; Theater.; Travelogs.; Portraits.; Criticism.; England |v Juvenile fiction.; English fiction |y 19th century.; Announcements.; Illustrations.; Interviews.; Drawings; Articles.; Teenage girls |v Fiction.; Paintings (visual works); Serials.; Magazines (Periodicals); Watercolors (paintings); Cartoons -- 1890-1900; Cartoons and children
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine," Volume I, Number 1, 1897 October (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Proprietors: “The Misses Strickland of Holmdale, Tweedy Road, Bromley, Kent [England]”
    Editor[s]: Stanley Hastings Tatham with T.J. Remington, Jr.
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, Diana Mary Strickland, H. Cooper Chadwick, J. Hauffman, Joseph Heap, L.F. Riches, Kathleen Brierley, Margaret Strickland, Oscar Brierly, R.S. Webb, Seymour Cobley, T. Williams
    Featuring: Announcements, Cartoon Illustrations, Editorial, Fiction Serial, Images, Ink Drawings, Interview, Music Columns, Newsprint Clippings, Poetry, Theater Review, Travel Writing - Bournemouth, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    39 Pages, Unbound
    Measurements: 8.75” x 10.5”
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine," Volume I, Number 2, 1897 November (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Editor: Stanley Hastings Tatham
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, Conway Fisher, H.C. Chadwick, L.F. Riches, Margaret Strickland, Otto B. Hatchard, R.W. Fenn, Stanley Hastings Tatham
    Featuring: Announcements, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial, Fictional Serial, Images, Ink Drawings, Interviews, Musical Column, Prize Competitions, “Sun Of My Soul” Hymn Set to Music by A. Pedro Lucci, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    Measurements: 9” x 10.5”
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine: The Christmas Number of the I.A.M," Volume I, Number 3 - with Ephemera, 1897 December (Box 6, Folder 9)
    [Proprietors: The Misses Strickland, of Holmdale, Tweedy Road, Bromley, Kent England]
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, Diana Mary Strickland, E. Linging, Joseph Heap, Margaret Strickland, Maud Kelvin, Otto B. Hatchard, Stanley Hastings Tatham
    Featuring: 1 “National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children” Pamphlet, Announcements, Art Supplement - Tower of London Etching, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial, Fictional Serial, Images, Ink Drawings, Poetry, “The I.A.M.” Sheet Music, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    Printed & Handwritten in Ink
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine," Volume I, Number 4, 1898 January (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Proprietors: “The Misses Strickland, of Holmdale, Tweedy Road, Bromley, Kent [England]”
    Edited by: Stanley Hastings Tatham
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, Ashton Shere, Bertha Bikker, Diana Mary Strickland, Joseph Heap, L.F. Riches, Margaret Strickland
    Featuring: Advertisement & Libretto for “Beauty & The Beast” at the Royal I.A.M. Theatre Pantomime [Part I], Advertisement for Royal County Theatre Kingston-on-Thames, Announcements, Cartoon Illustrations, Classified Listings, Correspondence, Editorial, Fictional Serial, Images, Ink Drawings, Interviews, Musical Column, Prize Competitions, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    45 Pages, Unbound
    Measurements: 8.25” x 11”
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine: Art, Music, Tales, Poetry, Drama - A Magazine for Amateurs, Contributed To By Amateurs, And Owned By Amateurs," Volume I, Number 5, 1898 March (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, Ashton Shere, Diana Mary Strickland, L.F. Riches, Joseph Heap, Margaret Strickland, Maud Kelvin, Otto B. Hatchard, Stanley Hastings Tatham, T. Townshend & E. Winder, W. Hastings Smith Featuring: Announcements, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial Column, Fiction Serials, Libretto for “Beauty & The Beast” at the Royal I.A.M. Theatre Pantomime [Part II], Music Column, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine: New Series," Volume II, Number 1, 1898 July (Box 6, Folder 12)
    “Owned, Published & Edited by the Misses Strickland, Holmdale, Tweedy Road, Bromley, Kent, [England]”
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, A.J. Hyde, Alice M. Sadler, A.W. Hyde, Diana Mary Strickland, Essex Smith, F.E. Smith, Margaret Strickland, Otto B. Hatchard, Stanley Hastings Tatham
    Featuring: Announcements, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial Column, Fiction Serials, Literary Column, Music Column, Poetry, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    28 Pages, Bound
    Measurements: 8.75” x 11.5”
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine," Volume II, Number 2, 1898 August (Box 6, Folder 13)
    “Edited by the Misses Strickland, Holmdale, Tweedy Road, Bromley, Kent, [England]”
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, A.J. Hyde, Alice M. Sadler, Diana Mary Strickland, Margaret Strickland, Otto B. Hatchard, Stanley Hastings Tatham
    Featuring: Announcements, [Bicycling] Chat, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial Column, Fiction - Short Stories, Poetry, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    30 Pages, Bound
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine," Volume II, Number 3, 1898 September (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, A.J. Hyde, “A Tonbridge Boy,” Charles T. Loveday, Diana Mary Strickland, Essex Smith, Margaret Strickland, Otto B. Hatchard
    Featuring: Announcements, [Bicycling] Chat & Correspondence & Useful Hints, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial Column, Fiction - Short Stories, Musical Column, Poetry, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    31 Pages, Unbound
    Measurements: 8.5” x 11.25”
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine," Volume II, Number 4, 1898 October (Box 7, Folder 2)
    “Sole Proprietors and Editresses: The Misses Strickland, Holmdale, Tweedy Road, Bromley, Kent, [England]”
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, A.J. Hyde, Charles T. Loveday, Diana Mary Strickland, John E. White, Otto B. Hatchard, T. Percival Smith, T.W. Ellis
    Featuring: Announcements, [Bicycling] Chat, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial Column, Fiction - Short Stories, Musical Column, Poetry, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    25 Pages, Bound
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine: A Magazine for Odd Moments," Volume II, Number 5, 1898 November (Box 7, Folder 3)
    “Owned, Published, & Edited by The Misses Strickland, Holmdale, Tweedy Road, Bromley, Kent, [England]”
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, Alice M. Sadler, Bertha Bikker, Charles T. Loveday, Diana Mary Strickland, H. Cooper Chadwick, Henry Joyce, J. Hauffman, Otto B. Hatchard, T. Percival Smith, T.W. Ellis, Walsh Trotter
    Featuring: Announcements, [Bicycling] Chat & Correspondence, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial Column, Fiction - Short Stories, Musical Column, Poetry, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    32 Pages, Bound
    Measurements: 9” x 11.25”
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine: Christmas," Volume II, Number 6, 1898 Christmas (Box 7, Folder 4)
    “Edited by The Misses Strickland, Holmdale, Tweedy Road, Bromley, Kent, [England]”
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, “A Board School Child,” Charles T. Loveday, Diana Mary Strickland, Henry Joyce, John E. Mace, Margaret Strickland, Otto B. Hatchard, Walter B. Bowen
    Featuring: Announcements, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial Column, Fiction - Short Stories, Musical Column, Poetry, Puzzles, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits
    50 Pages, Bound
    Measurements: 8.75” x 11.25”
  - "Illustrated Amateur Magazine," Volume III, Number 1, 1899 Christmas (Box 7, Folder 5)
    “Owned, Edited & Produced by the Misses Agnes, Margaret & Diana Strickland, Holmdale, Tweedy Road, Bromley, Kent, [England]”
    Contributors: Agnes Strickland, Alice N. Sadler, Beresford Pierce, Diana Mary Strickland, E.W. Linging, Henry Joyce, Margaret Strickland, Otto B. Hatchard, T. Percival Smith, W. Hastings Smith, William E. Kendall
    Featuring: Announcements, Bicycling Ballad, Cartoon Illustrations, Correspondence, Editorial Column, Fiction - Short Stories, Musical Column, Poetry, Puzzles, Watercolor Paintings - Landscapes, Portraits, Street Scene
    54 Pages, Bound
- Series IV: Diaries, Ephemera, Scrapbooks
  These materials are arranged alphabetically by record format or type, then chronologically if applicable. In the case that a record includes more than one date expression, the listing will begin with its earliest. If a record is physically undated, approximate ranges are provided. These records are noted "undated" and followed by a "circa" estimate determined by the range represented in the same series.